{"introPage":{"showIntroPage":false,"startButtonText":"Start Quiz","introduction":""},"progressType":"textual","passPercentage":70,"disableBackwardsNavigation":false,"randomQuestions":false,"endGame":{"showResultPage":true,"showSolutionButton":true,"showRetryButton":true,"noResultMessage":"Finished","message":"Your result:","overallFeedback":[{"from":0,"to":100}],"solutionButtonText":"Show solution","retryButtonText":"Retry","finishButtonText":"Finish","showAnimations":false,"skippable":false,"skipButtonText":"Skip video"},"override":{"checkButton":true},"texts":{"prevButton":"Previous question","nextButton":"Next question","finishButton":"Finish","textualProgress":"Question: @current of @total questions","jumpToQuestion":"Question %d of %total","questionLabel":"Question","readSpeakerProgress":"Question @current of @total","unansweredText":"Unanswered","answeredText":"Answered","currentQuestionText":"Current question"},"questions":[{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"How do you define a blockchain? Which of the following statements are correct?","answers":[{"text":"As the ordered list of all transactions since inception","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"As a well-ordered set of blocks","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"As a block of transactions","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"As a well-ordered set of data, on which all peers eventually agree on","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"As a shared real-time transaction network","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"In the context of blockchain, what is the most fundamental definition of a transaction?","answers":[{"text":"A transmission of a message between nodes","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"An atomic event that is allowed by the underlying protocol","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Exchange of a hash table between two peers","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"Choose all applicable properties of a Hash.","answers":[{"text":"A hash is deterministic, in that, calculating it twice yields the same result","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"A small change in the original value yields a smaller change in the hash than a big change in the original value","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"The probability of finding 2 different values that compute to the same hash is extremely low","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"What would be an instance of double-spending?","answers":[{"text":"The attacker sends 2 different transactions at the same time to the network, in order to send the same coin to 2 different recipients before the nodes can spot the fraud.","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"The attacker sends the coin to a recipient in exchange for a consideration, then waits to receive the consideration to then build a fork that does not contain the previous transaction and that is acceptable to the network.","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"The attacker sends the coin to a recipient in exchange for a consideration, then waits to receive the consideration to then send another transaction to cancel the first transaction.","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"How does Blockchain, as a non hierarchical approach, overcome the potential failures of a “classical” network?","answers":[{"text":"By making sure that every participant always has access to enough data to verify the integrity of ALL the data in the network.","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"By encrypting ALL data in the network.","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"By using certificates for all participants in the network, thus excluding malicious participants from the network.","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"What does a transaction do in a blockchain environment?","answers":[{"text":"Update one table on one machine","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Update separate tables of accounts for the whole network","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"In Blockchain, what is the truth, i.e. true state?","answers":[{"text":"The truth is what Satoshi Nakamoto says","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"The truth is what the developer community agrees on","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"The truth is what the biggest miner considers the truth","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"The truth is the set of data that all participants eventually agree on","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"What is the Byzantine General's Problem?","answers":[{"text":"How to distribute data in a hierarchy-free, permission-less and failure-prone network","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"How to transmit data in a hierarchy-free, permission-less and failure-prone network","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"How to reach consensus in a hierarchy-free, permission-less and failure-prone network","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"How to find peers in a hierarchy-free, permission-less and failure-prone network","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"In the context of blockchain, what is the most fundamental definition of a transaction?","answers":[{"text":"A transmission of a message between nodes","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"An atomic event that is allowed by the underlying protocol","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Exchange of a hash table between two peers","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"How does blockchain technology provide better ledger integrity?","answers":[{"text":"Blockchains can never be changed once data has been added","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"In order to change a piece of data in the past, all following blocks have to be recalculated","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"In a PoW network, for a malicious node to remove or insert transactions it would need to update the root hash of the containing block's Merkle tree, update the nonce of the containing block, update the hash of the containing block, and do the same for all subsequent blocks. Under what circumstances is that possible?","answers":[{"text":"If the attacker issues a high number of transactions","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"If the attacker controls more than 50% of the mining power in a blockchain network","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"Select all answers that are true for proof-of-work!","answers":[{"text":"Any node can propose new blocks","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Potential miners must get approval by the network before they can propose blocks","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"More than one miner can find a correct block in the same time","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"What is the difficulty in a blockchain network?","answers":[{"text":"The difficulty determines how likely it is for a miner to find a valid block","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"The difficulty sets the fees a user has to pay for a transaction","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"The difficulty sets how difficult it is for clients to connect to the network","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"Select all answers that are true for proof-of-stake!","answers":[{"text":"Anyone can propose new blocks, irrespective of the number of coins/tokens held","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Miners with a large stake in the network can propose blocks","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"More than one miner can find a correct block in the same time","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"The hypothesis for PoS suggests that participants with a large stake are more trustworthy","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"Why does one talk about eventual consensus in context of blockchain networks?","answers":[{"text":"It might take time for all nodes to agree on the substance and order of data","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"It might take time until the approval authority verifies the consensus","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"Identify the core characteristics of public blockchain networks.","answers":[{"text":"Publicly accessible","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Guaranteed transaction privacy","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Hierarchy-free","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Using crypto-economic incentives","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Using a central clearing house for all transactions","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"What does full decentralisation in public networks mean? Choose the right answer:","answers":[{"text":"It means that decentralised public networks provide access only to approved participants","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"It means that decentralised public networks are fully accessible","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"How are changes in public blockchain protocols verified?","answers":[{"text":"Changes are verified by a government entity","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Changes are validated by community members","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Changes are verified by core developers","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"How can public blockchain networks defend against malicious behaviour?","answers":[{"text":"By enforcing revocable access rights","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"By introducing game theoretic elements","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"What is the difference between a public and a private blockchain network?","answers":[{"text":"Public networks always use a different consensus algorithm","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Public networks are controlled by the SEC unlike private networks","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Private networks restrict user access unlike public networks","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"Which of the following statements about permissioned blockchains are true:","answers":[{"text":"In permissioned blockchains an individual or group of participants holds the authority to validate blocks","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Permissioned blockchains restrict the actor's involvement regarding the consensus state","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"In permissioned blockchains smart contract creation is open to all network members","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"Why do managed blockchains not have to mitigate the Byzantine General's Problem?","answers":[{"text":"Because managed blockchains do not use any consensus algorithm","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Because managed blockchains operate in a predictable environment with elements of authority and hierarchy","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Because managed blockchains do not use proof-of-work as a consensus algorithm","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"Compared to public blockchains, which are open to everyone and do not have entry barriers, in managed blockchains accessibility can be decided by:","answers":[{"text":"A central authority","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"All participants which belong to the network","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Everyone in- and outside of the network","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"Identify advantages of managed blockchain networks","answers":[{"text":"Public accessibility","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Better scalability","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Limited participation","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Decentralised governance","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"What are the key reasons for managed/private networks to exist?","answers":[{"text":"To open the door to complex calculations","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"To protect confidential data","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"To increase network performance and reduce transaction times","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"Why can ledger integrity in financial infrastructures be improved with blockchain technology?","answers":[{"text":"Because managed networks have integrated alert systems in case of inconsistencies","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Because each function execution is signed with a private key and every addition to the ledger constitutes a state change","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"Why is change management so important for blockchains?","answers":[{"text":"Because there is no central authority in blockchains","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Because an unmanaged client update can have disastrous implications","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"What is Tezos?","answers":[{"text":"A P2P, open-source blockchain protocol","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"A decentralised data base","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"An oracle to fetch blockchain data","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"What was Tezos first protocol upgrade?","answers":[{"text":"Athens","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Babylon","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Carthage","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Edo","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"What was the name of the first blockchain protocol?","answers":[{"text":"Bitcoin","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Ethereum","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Hyperledger Fabric","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Corda","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"Why is maintaining a secure P2P networks a challenge?","answers":[{"text":"Because of the central authority managing the network","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"[x} Because of the potential for remote exploits","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Because of interconnectivity","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"What are main attributes of DPoS? Please select the correct ones!","answers":[{"text":"Nodes proof their ammount of work by fulfiling a task of arbitrary difficulty","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"There is a fixed set of validators","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Witnesses secure the network","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Delegates are selected based on their stake to supervise network governance","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"What of the following are properties of a smart contract?","answers":[{"text":"Self-evolving","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Self-executing","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Self-enforcing","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Self-verifying","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Self-writing","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"How does Tezos amend its protocol, i.e. introduces change?","answers":[{"text":"Through its on-chain governance","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Through hard forks","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"Through updates from their core developers","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"Which are stages of the Tezos amendment process? Please select!","answers":[{"text":"the proposal period","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"the exploration vote period or testing_vote period","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"the testing period","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"the promotion vote period","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"the adoption period","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"In Tezos, when do bakers vote on-chain?","answers":[{"text":"during the end of the proposal period","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"during the testing period","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"during the testing_vote period","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"during the promotion vote period","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"during the adoption period","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"What is the consensus mechanism in Tezos called?","answers":[{"text":"PoW","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"DPoS","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"PoS","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"LPoS","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}},{"library":"H5P.MultiChoice 1.14","params":{"question":"What is a baker?","answers":[{"text":"A validator node","correct":true,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"A mining node","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}},{"text":"A delegate node","correct":false,"tipsAndFeedback":{}}],"behaviour":{"singleAnswer":true}}}]}